

## ALEXANDRA (ALEX) GRIEVES

#### OVERVIEW

I am a multi-disciplinary, award-winning strategy director with over 10 years' experience working across geographies, sectors and agencies. As a result of my diverse experience, I take a holistic, collaborative and culturally sensitive approach to problem-solving and project leadership. I'm a passionate champion of physical and mental health, and am interested in helping brands, organisations and communities support people's wellbeing in creative, innovative and sustainable ways.

## EXPERIENCE

Strategy Director Feb 2021 – present

Freelance London UK

Brand and communications strategy to bring brands' vision of health and wellbeing to life. Recent projects include: defining a unique vision of 'wellness' and setting the strategy for a new all-inclusive wellness concept for **JW Marriott**; articulating a new food & beverage proposition for **The Ritz-Carlton**; helping **John Lewis & Partners** activate their new Purpose internally; growing nutrition brand **Huel** by articulating their growth audience and a 2021/2022 comms framework; repositioning HR leader **XpertHR** to be more relevant and human in the post-Covid future of work; and helping ITV-backed Gen Z lifestyle platform **Woo** create a 'safe space' for wellness discovery.

Founder | Editor Apr 2021 – present

#### Wellwatching (wellwatching.substack.com)

London UK

Wellwatching sits at the intersection of wellbeing and the built environment, exploring the places and spaces – both physical and digital – that help us feel well. In my newsletter, I interview a variety of people on how architecture, design, urban planning, digital media and related fields can better support people's wellbeing in the future.

# Brand Planning Director

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020

VCCP London UK

Led planning on a variety of Cadbury seasonal equity and sub-brands, spanning global positioning work to cut-through local campaigns. Highlights include: making the limited-edition **Twirl Orange** the #1 UK singles bar of 2020; making **Cadbury Secret Santa** pandemic-proof; engaging families with the **Heroes League** gaming tournament; and developing a new purpose narrative and creative strategy to give Freddo new meaning among parents & kids.

#### **Integrated Strategy Director**

Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

## Team Horizon: WPP cross-agency team for British Airways

London UK

Cultivated collaborative relationships with a wide variety of agency- and client-side specialists to guide strategic solutions, most notably a new approach to BA's **January Sale** that resulted in +8% revenue on key routes. Co-led repositioning of **BA Holidays** and **BA Gatwick**'s short-haul leisure proposition.

## Global Associate Strategy Director

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

#### Maxus Global Media (now Wavemaker)

London UK

Part of core pitch teams to win and lead day-to-day planning on multi-market Triumph Lingerie / Sloggi (\$35m) and Helly Hansen (\$3m) accounts. Helped **Helly Hansen** better engage outdoor enthusiasts on a small budget.

WPP Fellow Sep 2011 – Jan 2015
WPP Group Global

Selected as one of 10 Fellows from 2000 international applicants to join the WPP Fellowship: the world's leading global marketing communications training programme. Fellowship positions are detailed below.

**Senior Strategist** [Year 3, WPP Fellowship]

Jun 2014 – Dec 2015

Maxus Global Media (now Wavemaker)

London UK

Developed media strategies for FMCG clients and new business pitches.

**Content Strategist, Brand Solutions** [Year 3, WPP Fellowship]

Jan 2014 - Jun 2014

Virtue, the creative agency by VICE Media

London UK

Developed strategies for global brands to connect with youth audiences via VICE's editorial platforms.

**Strategic Planner** [Year 2, WPP Fellowship]

Nov 2012 – Nov 2013

**Ogilvy**Developed local brand positioning for global clients such as Revlon, Heinz and Coca-Cola.

**Strategic Consultant** [Year 1, WPP Fellowship]

Sep 2011 - Oct 2012

Kantar Consulting (formerly The Futures Company)

New York NY

May 2017

Cape Town SA

Managed trends & futures projects and workshops for blue chip companies, including a trends expedition for General Motors on the future of urban transport.

#### Internships

WildChina Travel - Beijing, China | Coca-Cola - Beijing, China | DesignTrust - Connecticut, USA Woods TV - Paris, France | glacéau vitaminwater - Vermont, USA

Advanced Certificate, Communications Planning – Merit | Institute of Practitioners in Advertising

#### **EDUCATION**

<b>B.A., Chinese Language and Literature – <i>High Honours</i>   Middlebury College (USA)</b>	May 2009
ACCOLADES	
DMA Awards: Gold / Best Launch Campaign; Best Use of Social Media – Cadbury Twirl Orange Presale	Dec 2021
The Lovie Awards:	Nov 2021
Silver / Mobile & Experiential Marketing – Cadbury Secret Santa	
Winner / People's Lovie – Cadbury Secret Santa	
APG Creative Strategy Awards: Silver – Cadbury Twirl Orange	Oct 2021
Creative Circle Awards:	Sep 2021
<ul> <li>Gold / Best Social Media Campaign; Best Product Launch – Cadbury Twirl Orange Presale</li> </ul>	
<ul> <li>Bronze / Best Digital-Led Campaign; Best Digital Activation – Cadbury Twirl Orange Presale</li> </ul>	
Twitter's most creative brand campaigns 2020: Winner / Product Launch – Cadbury Twirl Orange	Jan 2021
Campaign Media Awards: Highly Commended / travel & leisure category – British Airways January Sale	Jan 2020
Campaign Tech Awards: Winner / Best Use of Tech in OOH – British Airways January Sale	May 2019
Cannes Young Lions UK: Runner-Up / Media category	May 2016

## MORE ABOUT ME

- Diverse international background: born in Hong Kong; experience living and working across Mainland China, Hong Kong, USA, South Africa and the UK.
- Conversational Mandarin Chinese; basic understanding of French & Spanish.